Shizu's lingering wish, her regret,
（リムル）
シズの心残り 未練…
that she entrusted to Rimuru,
シズがリムルに託したのは
turned out to be children who'd been
summoned here in an incomplete form.
不完全な状態で この世界に
召喚された子供たちだった
Their bodies, not fully matured,
子供の未成熟な体では
were unable to control the immense
magicule energy within them.
体内の膨大な魔素(まそ)エネルギーを
制御できない
Before long, that energy would go berserk,
遠からず エネルギーは暴走し
destroying their bodies
and dooming them to die.
その体が崩壊して
死ぬ運命にあった
Rimuru conjectured that the
reason Shizu survived longer,
同じく子供のときに召喚された
シズが生きながらえたのは
イフリートを宿すことによって
体内のエネルギーを
despite being summoned as a child herself,
may have been because Ifrit dwelled within her
body, giving her control of that energy.
制御できたからではないかと
推測したリムルは
So, to save the children,
子供たちを救うため 上位精霊を
he decided to get superior
spirits to inhabit their bodies.
その身に宿らせることを決意した
Shizu-san, I swear I'm
going to save these kids.
（リムル）
シズさん 絶対に
こいつらを救ってみせるから
That Time I Got Reincarnated as a Slime
Episode 22: Conquering the Labyrinth
This is the entrance?
（リムル）ここが入り口か
So the Dwelling of Spirits
is right inside here.
この奥に
精霊の棲家(すみか)があるんだな
Are you guys ready for this?
覚悟はできているか？
Once we go in, we may never come out.
入ったら
二度と戻れないかもしれない
O-Of course I'm ready!
（ケンヤ）も… もちろんだぜ！
（ゲイル）はい！
Yes!
I'm fine.
（リョウタ）大丈夫です…
（アリス）
こ… 怖くなんてないんだからね！
I-I'm not scared at all!
Ranga, if anything happens,
take care of them.
（リムル）
ランガ 何かあったら みんなを頼む
Your students are my students, Master.
（ランガ）
主(あるじ)の生徒は 我が生徒も同じ
I will protect them with my life!
この命に懸けて
守り抜いてみせます！
Good.
行くぞ
Let's go.
It's just a straight path.
（ケンヤ）ずっと 一本道だな
What the heck?
For a labyrinth, this looks easy!
（アリス）
何よ… 迷宮っていっても
大したことないわね！
B-But something seems weird about it...
（リョウタ）
でっ でも なんか変な感じ…
（リムル）絶対に はぐれるなよ
Whatever you do,
don't wander away from the group.
R-Right!
（一同）は… はい！
It looks like a straight path,
（リムル）
一本道に見えるが
but there are traps meant to confuse your
sense of direction all over the place.
方向感覚を狂わせる罠(わな)が
あちこちに仕掛けられている
With human senses alone,
人間の感覚だけでは
we might end up unable to either
move forward or go back.
進むことも戻ることも
できなくなるかもしれない
I'm glad I have my mental map.
脳内マップがあって よかった〜
What are those voices?
Where are they coming from?
（ケンヤ）
何だ この声？　どっから…
It sounds like they're
resonating inside our heads.
（ゲイル）
頭に直接 響いてるみたいだ
Powerful thought transference...
no, telepathy?
（リムル）
強力な念話…
いや テレパシーか？
Not very amusing, visitors.
（ラミリス）つまらぬぞ！　客人よ
Be more afraid. Feel more fear!
もっと怖がれ　もっとおびえよ
Good, good! It's no fun for
me if you show no fear!
（ラミリス）いいね いいね
もっと怖がってくれないと
つまらない！
Are you a spirit who lives here?
（リムル）
ここに住んでる精霊さんかな？
We need to talk to some superior spirits.
俺たちは 上位精霊に用があるんだ
If possible, could you take us
to them without impeding us?
できたら邪魔しないで
案内をしてほしいんだけど
What an amusing thing to say!
面白いこと言うね
Of course, of course. I'll tell you.
いいよ いいよ　教えてあげる
Oh, that was easier than I expected.
（リムル）おっ 案外 あっさり
But before that...
その前に…
Before that?
（リムル）その前に？
Sensei, look...
先生 あれ…
Looks like an invitation to me.
どうやら お誘いのようだな
行くしかないか
I guess we'll have to go.
Hey, it's a dead end.
行き止まりだぞ
No rush, no rush.
（ラミリス）慌てない 慌てない
Small World!
“迷宮創造(チイサナセカイ)”
Well? Amazing, don't you think?
どう？　すごいでしょ
Wow...
（ケンヤ）すっげえ…
Now, it's time for your test!
（ラミリス）
さあ 試練の時間だよ！
Whether it's in an anime or a game,
（リムル）
ゲームといい アニメといい
the shady characters' eyes always glow red.
怪しい魔物って
目が赤く光るよなあ
Hey, is our "test" to defeat this thing?
（リムル）
おい！　試練って
こいつを倒せばいいのか？
Ding-dong! That is correct!
（ラミリス）
ピンポ〜ン♪　そのとおり〜
Seriously? This'll be easy.
（リムル）
なんだ 簡単じゃねえか
Shall I handle it?
（ランガ）我が いきましょうか？
No, you protect the kids for me.
（リムル）
いや お前は
こいつらを守っててくれ
If anything happens to me,
get them out of here.
俺に何かあったら
みんなを連れて逃げろ
Right!
Sensei...
先生…
It'll be fine. Sensei's strong.
大丈夫だ 先生は強いんだから
What's this? What's this,
what's this, what's this?
You're doing this alone? Overconfidence
is a dangerous thing, you know.
１人でやるの？
自信過剰は危ないよ〜
Great Sage, Appraisal.
（リムル）
大賢者(だいけんじゃ)“解析鑑定”
Answer.
（大賢者）
解(かい)…
Answer
It is a golem with a body made of magisteel.
全身が魔鋼(まこう)で作られたゴーレムです
（リムル）
う〜ん ヤベえな こいつ…
Damn, this thing's intense.
Its magicule energy is off the charts.
魔素エネルギー量が ハンパねえ
It's even stronger than that
thing from the other day.
この間の あいつより強いぞ
どうすっかなあ…
What to do?
It looks pretty damn heavy, too...
すげえ重そうだし
Hey, what the hell?! It's trying to kill me!
おいおい！
殺しにかかってるじゃねえか！
どこが試練だよ！
How is this a "test"?!
Precisely! Get careless, and you're dead!
（ラミリス）そのとおり！
油断してると死んじゃうよ？
Think you can win? Think you can win?
勝てるかな　勝てるかな♪
I feel as though she's making fun of me...
（リムル）
なんか バカにされてるような…
It's definitely fast,
but I can evade it easily.
速いっちゃ速いけど
余裕で回避できる
The only question is how to defeat it...
あとは どうやって倒すかだな
Since it's made of metal,
Black Thunder probably won't work.
（リムル）
金属だから
“黒雷(こくらい)”は通じないだろうな
The electric shock would run through
the ground and wipe us all out.
地面に電流が流れて おしまいだ
I doubt I can cut it with a sword, either.
剣では斬れそうにないし…
あれを使うか？
Should I use... that?
Sensei!
（クロエ）先生！
（リムル）ん？
It's all right!
There's nothing to worry about!
（リムル）
大丈夫！
な〜んにも心配しなくていい
Hey! If you apologize now,
I'll let you off the hook.
（リムル）
おい！
今のうちに謝るなら許してやる
If you don't, I'll bust this
thing up. Is that okay with you?
だが そうしないなら
こいつを壊すけど いいんだな？
（ラミリス）アッハハハ
Interesting! Yes, of course! Of course!
（ラミリス）面白い！
いいよ いいともさ！
やってごらんよ
Go ahead and try!
Arcane Thread Fetters!
操糸妖縛陣(そうしようばくじん)！
What?! My Elemental Colossus!
アタシの
エレメンタルコロッサスが！
お別れの挨拶を言っときな
Better say your goodbyes now.
Wh-Wh-Wh-Wh-Wh—
Hell Flare!
（リムル）ヘルフレア！
（ゲイル）す… すごい！
I-Incredible!
I-It's nothing that special, but... Wow...
（アリス）
たっ 大したことないけど…
すごい
（ラミリス）ウソだ！　そんな…
No! This can't be!
It only took one hit?!
たった 一撃で！
Well, that about does it.
まっ こんなもんだ
Sensei, you're awesome!
（ケンヤ）先生 すっげえ！
Yeah! Yeah!
You really are as strong as Shizu-sensei!
（ゲイル）
やっぱり
シズ先生と同じくらい強いんだね！
Well, of course he could beat that thing!
（アリス）あのくらい当然よ！
なんでアリスが威張ってんの？
Why are you talking tough, Alice?
Now, then...
（リムル）さてと…
（一同）ん？
If you don't want to be burned
to a crisp, come on out here.
焼き尽くされたくなければ
さっさと出てこいよ
I can see where you're hiding.
隠れている場所は
お見通しなんだぜ
Right!
（ラミリス）
はい！　はいはい はいはい…
Right, right, right, right...
Humiliating though it is, I have
come in response to your call!
（ラミリス）
たった今
恥ずかしながら
呼ばれて
やってまいりました〜！
A Fairy?
（ゲイル）妖精？
（クロエ）かわいい…
She's cute...
Who are you?
お前は？
Ta-da!
じゃじゃ〜ん！
I am one of th—
我こそは偉大な…
ゲホッ！
She bit her tongue.
（クロエ）噛(か)んだ
（アリス）痛そうね
That had to hurt.
Must've been her first time speaking
without telepathy in a while.
（ゲイル）テレパシーばっかりで
久しぶりに
しゃべったんじゃない？
You okay?
（リムル）大丈夫か？
I'm fine, I'm fine...
（ラミリス）
だいじょぶ だいじょぶ…
I am one of the Ten Great Demon Lords,
我こそは 偉大なる十大魔王が一人
Ramiris of the Labyrinth!
迷宮妖精のラミリスである！
（ケンヤ）はあ？
（リムル）魔王？
A Demon Lord?
Know your place! You should be groveli—
頭(ず)が高いぞ　ひざまずくがい…
うぴょっ！
Ow!
What the heck was that?!
な… 何すんのよさ！
A chop?
（リムル）チョップ？
（ラミリス）そうじゃなくて！
Not the point!
How could you even be a Demon Lord, anyway?
（リムル）大体 なにが魔王だ
（ラミリス）うっ…
吐くなら もっとマシなウソを言え
If you're gonna lie, make it believable.
There's no way a kid like you
could become a Demon Lord.
お前みたいなガキが
魔王になれるわけがないだろ？
Don't call me a kid! How rude!
（ラミリス）
ガキ言うなや！
ホンマ失礼なヤツ
What else could I be but a Demon Lord?!
アタシが
魔王以外の何だっていうのさ！
アホの子？
An idiot?
Who're you calling an idiot?!
誰がアホの子や！
おバカさん？
A simpleton?
そうそう おバカさんやで
Right, right. I'm a simpleton.
って…
Hey!
Don't think just saying
it politely makes it okay!
丁寧に言えばいい
ってもんやないわ〜い！
Hmm... I have a friend named
Milim who's a Demon Lord,
ミリムっていう魔王の友達がいるが
and you look too weak to even compare to her.
お前 そいつと比べようもないほど
弱そうだが？
ふんぬ！
Hmph! You moron!
バ〜カ！
バカ バカ バカ バカ！
Moron! Moron! Moron!
Moron! Moron! You're a moron!
あんたはバカじゃ〜！
ハア ハア…
Now, listen... Milim is known to
us as the Demon Lord of Absurdity.
あのねえ あんた
ミリムって
理不尽魔王って呼ばれてるの
She thinks she can just solve
everything with strength.
〝何でも力で
解決しちゃいま〜す〞って
そんな理不尽の権化と
It's beyond rude to compare my lovely
self to that embodiment of absurdity!
可憐(かれん)なアタシを
比べるなんて
失礼なんてもんじゃ
ないよ〜！
I need you to understand that,
or we'll have big problems!
そこんとこ ちゃんと
理解してくれないと困るわけ
困るわけ！
Big problems!
Big! Problems!
Damn, she's obnoxious.
（リムル）
うるっさいなあ こいつ
あんたも
ちょっと おかしいんじゃなくて？
And isn't there something off about you, too?
What's your deal? How is it you can
use a haphazard move like that?
何なの？　なんで
あんなデタラメな技 使えんのよ
フウ〜
I wish you wouldn't be so reckless!
むちゃしないでほしいわけ！
Do you really know Milim?
あんた ホントに
ミリムと知り合いなの？
We became friends recently.
最近 友達になった
（ラミリス）ふ〜ん
Wait a minute...
ちょっと待って…
あんた もしかして
Are you the slime that became the new
leader of the Great Forest of Jura?
ジュラの大森林で 新しく盟主に
なったっていうスライムなんじゃ？
That's right. I'm impressed you know that.
（リムル）
そうだけど よく分かったな
Oh! So it's true!
（ラミリス）あっ やっぱり！
Sensei...
（ケンヤ）先生…
（アリス）スライムって？
You're a slime?
Oh, yeah.
S-Sensei is...
せ… 先生が！
...a slime?!
スライム？
That's how it is.
（リムル）ってわけだ
Cute...
かわいい
Sorry to surprise you.
驚かして悪かったな
Awesome!
（ケンヤ）すっげえ！
You're a slime, but you're so strong!
（リョウタ）スライムなのに強い！
Th-That's not a big deal, okay?!
（アリス）
た… 大したことないんだからね！
I guess anything goes! Amazing, Sensei!
（ゲイル）
何でもあり
先生 さすがです！
I'll tell you all the
details some other time.
（リムル）
まあ 詳しい話は また今度な
ちょっと！
アタシのこと忘れてない？
Excuse me! Have you forgotten that I'm here?!
わりい わりい
Sorry about that.
で なんで俺のこと知ってんだ？
So, how did you know about me?
Milim showed up here for
the first time in ages,
（ラミリス）
ミリムのヤツが
ちょ〜久々に やって来て
bragging about how she'd
found herself a "bestie."
マブダチが出来たって
自慢しやがったの
I sneered at her then,
but it turned out to be true!
鼻で笑ってやったのに
ホントだったなんて！
If Milim was here,
（リムル）
ミリムが来たってことは
maybe that means she wasn't lying
about being a Demon Lord...
こいつが魔王というのも
ウソではない？　のかな…
What's with that doubting look in your eyes?
その疑いの まなざしは何？
You'd better believe I'm a Demon Lord!
アタシが魔王だって
信じなさいよね！
She could tell I was doubting it...
（リムル）
疑ってんのバレたか
あ〜ん
It's so good! Yep, so good!
おいしい！
うん おいしい〜
She eats a ton. Where is she putting it all?
（リムル）
よく食うな
どこに入るんだ？　その量
I never intended to kill
you, or even hurt you.
（ラミリス）
殺すつもりも ケガさせるつもりも
なかったのよさ
Really, now?
（リムル）ホントかよ〜？
（ラミリス）ホントだって
Yes, really.
I just wanted to have a
little fun scaring you,
（ラミリス）
ビビらせて ちょっと楽しんで
and then gallantly save you,
so you'd respect me!
そのあと さっそうと助けて
尊敬される予定だったの
What the heck?
何だ それ？
Acting in my own play?
（ラミリス）自作自演ってやつ？
なのに エレメンタルコロッサスを
壊しちゃうなんて！
But then you actually destroyed
my Elemental Colossus!
I finally completed it after fiddling
so much with that toy I found!
拾ってきたオモチャ いじくって
や〜っと完成させたのに
しかたないだろ
What choice did I have?
I thought it was kill or be killed.
殺(や)らなきゃ殺られると
思ったんだから
Also, that thing was super
sophisticated, you know!
大体ねえ あれは
すっごい高性能だったんだよ
I used earth spirits to control its weight,
（ラミリス）
地の精霊で重量を操作して
水の精霊で関節を動かし
water spirits to move its joints,
fire spirits to generate power,
火の精霊で動力を発生させ
and wind spirits to regulate heat,
making it a composite of all the elements!
風の精霊で熱を調整する
元素の集大成！
I made it using the very
best spirit engineering!
精霊工学の粋(すい)を集めて作ったのに！
Spirit engineering?
精霊工学？
Could that be...
（リムル）
それって もしかして…
One of the projects he'd been under pressure
to complete, the Magisoldier Project...
（カイジン）
功を焦ったベスターの計画のひとつ
魔装兵(まそうへい)計画が…
went up in smoke.
ポシャっちまった
You mean the Magisoldier
that the Dwarves and Elves
ドワルゴンでドワーフとエルフが
共同で開発しようとしてた
were working together to invent in Dwargon?
（リムル）魔装兵ってやつ？
（ラミリス）ん？
Ding-dong, ding-dong! So you know about that!
ピンポン ピンポ〜ン！
よく知ってるね
That project failed
あの計画は“精霊魔導核(せいれいまどうかく)”っていう
because they couldn't produce the
magicore that would serve as its heart.
心臓部を作れなくて失敗したんだよ
Besides, there's no way it
could've withstood spirit power
そもそもね
通常の鋼材で作ったって
if it was made of normal steel.
精霊力に
耐えられるはずないのにね〜
After it went berserk and fell apart,
暴走して壊れちゃった外殻が
捨ててあったから
they threw out its shell,
which I brought here and restored!
持って帰って復元したの！
Could I be a genius?
もしかして アタシって天才？
Aren't I amazing? Aren't I amazing?!
すごくない？　すごくな〜い？
Obnoxious...
（リムル）
ウザい…
That really is amazing, though.
だが 確かに すごいな
She managed to complete the research
that Vesta's team failed at.
ベスターたちでさえ失敗した研究を
自己流で完成させるとは
She just looks like an idiot,
アホの子にしか見えないが
but this Demon Lord Ramiris
might actually be amazing.
このラミリスっていう魔王
本当に すごいのかも
Okay. I get that you're amazing.
（リムル）
よし すごいのは分かった
そんな すごい君を見込んで
頼みがある
And having seen how amazing you
are, I have a favor to ask.
Huh? A favor? Why should I do what you—
（ラミリス）はあ？　頼み？
なんでアタシが
あんたなんかの言うこと…
聞く 聞く！
I'll listen! I'll listen!
I feel like listening to you now!
聞いてあげてもいい気が
してきたのでありま〜す！
It's good to be so accepting.
素直なのは いいことだ
（ラミリス）ハア…
Of course, I won't ask
you to do it for nothing.
もちろん タダとは言わない
協力してくれたら
If you'll help me, I'll whip
up a new golem for you.
俺が新しいゴーレムを
用意しようじゃないか
So start talking.
早く話しなさいよ
I explained everything about the
kids to her, keeping nothing hidden.
（リムル）
俺は子供たちの事情を
何も隠すことなく全てを説明した
That I wanted superior
spirits to inhabit them
体内のエネルギーを制御するため
上位精霊を宿らせたい
so they could control the energy within them,
and that this was why I wanted
to go to the Dwelling of Spirits.
だから
精霊の棲家に行きたいのだと
I see.
（ラミリス）なるほどね〜
Those kids have it pretty rough.
みんな 苦労してるんだねえ
Right?
（リムル）だろ？
That's why I want you to introduce
me to the Queen of Spirits.
だからさ 精霊女王とやらに
紹介してほしいんだよ
Hmm?
Oh, didn't I tell you?
ああ〜 言ってなかったっけ
アタシだよ
That's me.
Huh?
I'm saying the Queen of Spirits
（ラミリス）だから 精霊女王
is me.
アタシのことだよ
This is no time for joking aro—
冗談 言ってる場合じゃ…
（ラミリス）
ブブーッ！　冗談じゃありませ〜ん
Bzzt! It's no joke!
It's true!
ホントです〜！
Okay, look...
あのね 君…
なんで魔王が
精霊の女王やってるんだよ
Why would a Demon Lord be Queen of Spirits?
Bzzt again! You got it backwards!
（ラミリス）
また ブブーッ！
逆で〜す！
Backwards?
（リムル）逆？
The Queen of Spirits fell from
grace to become a Demon Lord!
（ラミリス）
精霊の女王が
堕落して魔王になっちゃったんです
Is "fell from grace" something
you'd say about yourself?
自分で堕落したって言うか？
Well, I did fall from grace.
（ラミリス）
だって 堕落しちゃったんだもん
It's so easy to fall...
墜(お)ちるのって 簡単よね…
Oh, come to think of it,
he fell from grace, too.
あっ そういえば
あいつも堕落したんだった
あいつ？
"He"?
レオンちゃん？
Leon-chan?
Apparently, he had something
he wanted to look into,
（ラミリス）
あいつさあ
なんか調べ物があったみたいで
so he called in a superior
spirit from ancient times,
大昔の上位精霊を呼び寄せてさあ
and they forged a contract. Shocking, right?
契約 結んだんだよね〜
びっくりだよね
So then I had no choice,
で しかたないから
精霊女王のアタシは
レオンちゃんを勇者と認定して
as Queen of Spirits,
to recognize Leon-chan as a Hero
and grant him the divine
protection of the spirits.
精霊の加護を授けたってわけ
Hang on! Why did a guy who was
declared a Hero become a Demon Lord?
（リムル）ちょっと待て
なんで勇者に認定したヤツが
魔王になってんだ？
He must have fallen from grace.
（ラミリス）
だから 堕落したんじゃないの？
Maybe he copied me!
もしかして
アタシをマネたのかもよ
魔王って
堕落してなるものなのかよ…
So you have to fall from
grace to become a Demon Lord?
Of course, I could knock
him out with one punch!
（ラミリス）
まっ アタシなら
ワンパンで倒せるけどね
Easy peasy. One punch, one punch!
余裕 余裕
ワンパン ワンパン！
（リムル）
ウソだな
Liar.
Seriously, though, Heroes can
become Demon Lords in this world?
それより この世界
勇者が魔王になったりするのか？
Come to think of it, Leon-chan
said something pretty outrageous.
（ラミリス）
そういや レオンちゃん
むちゃなことも言ってたなあ
He asked me to summon a specific
individual from another world.
（ラミリス）
異世界から
特定の人物を召喚してくれって
A specific one?
（リムル）特定の？
As if that's even possible! What a moron!
（ラミリス）
無理に決まってんのにね
バッカじゃん！
He looked like he might cry!
泣きそうな顔してたね
いや あれは泣いてた
No, he did cry! It's not
a stretch to say he cried!
そう
泣いてたと言っても過言ではない！
Pretty impudent for such a crybaby!
That moron! Just one punch! One punch!
泣き虫のくせに生意気なんだよ
バ〜カ！
ワンパンだよ ワンパン！
（リムル）
う〜ん よく分からんが…
I'm not too sure,
but this Demon Lord Leon might
be more trouble than I thought.
魔王レオンってヤツは
俺の考えている以上に
やっかいな相手なのかもしれないな
But seriously, is this chick gonna be okay?
しかし こいつ 大丈夫か？
Won't Leon wipe her out if he finds out
she's trash-talking him behind his back?
陰口たたいてるのがバレたら
レオンに消されるんじゃ…
If it were me, I can safely
say I'd wipe her out.
俺だったら
余裕で こいつを消す自信がある
ん？　ちょっと あんた
Hey! You're thinking something
really rude right now, aren't you?!
今 とっても失礼なこと
考えてない？
いや 全く
Nope, not at all!
で 精霊の棲家に
案内してくれるのか？
So, are you going to take me
to the Dwelling of Spirits?
（ラミリス）
アタシはね 魔王であると同時に
聖なる者の導き手
You know, I'm not just a Demon Lord.
I'm also the Guide of Saints
and the Fairy of the Labyrinth, as
well as the former Queen of Spirits.
迷宮妖精であり
精霊女王でもあったの
I have the duty of bestowing
レオンちゃんに そうしたように
the spirits' divine protection upon
Heroes, as I did with Leon-chan.
勇者に精霊の加護を授ける役目も
担ってるんだよ
So you don't need to to worry.
だから 安心するがいいさ
I am impartial.
公平だからね アタシは
I am the one who maintains
the balance of this world.
アタシが… アタシこそが
世界のバランスを保つ者なのだよ
いいよ　召喚に協力してあげる
Very well.
I will aid you in your summoning.
I hope you can call forth powerful spirits.
すごい精霊を呼び出すといいさ
Treyni?
（ラミリス）トレイニー？
Wow, it's good to hear
that those girls are well.
へえ〜
あの子たちも元気にしてるんだ
They were such cute little
spirits back in the day.
昔は小さくて
かわいい精霊だったんだよ
Huh?
あれ？　トレイニーさんは
今の精霊女王とは接点ないって
But Treyni-san said she had no connection
with the current Queen of Spirits.
Ah, right...
（ラミリス）ああ それね
Even after dying and being reborn,
アタシは死んで生まれ変わっても
前世の記憶を残してるからね
I still retain my memories
of my previous life.
I guess they don't know that.
（ラミリス）
あの子たち
そのこと知らないんじゃないかな？
We got split up a long time ago,
and I haven't seen them since.
ずっと昔に はぐれて
それっきりだったし
Tell them to come pay me a visit sometime.
また今度 遊びに来てって伝えてよ
（リムル）分かった
Will do.
I can't wait!
（ラミリス）楽しみだな〜
（一同）わあ〜
So this is...
（リムル）ここが…
The deepest part of the Labyrinth,
the Dwelling of Spirits.
（ラミリス）
迷宮の最深部 精霊の棲家
It's a lot like Veldora's cave.
（リムル）
ヴェルドラの洞窟に似てるな
It's overflowing with natural energy.
自然エネルギーに満ちあふれている
And there are superior spirits here?
ここに上位精霊がいるんだな
There are, but they have wills of their own.
（ラミリス）
いるけど…
上位精霊には自我があってね
They'll only respond to your
summons if they feel like it.
呼び出しに応じてくれるかは
気分しだいだよ
What happens if they don't come?
来てくれなかったら どうするの？
エネルギーを切り取って
You can just separate some of the energy
and create a new superior spirit.
新たな上位精霊を
生み出せばいいんだよ
Create one?
（リョウタ）生み出す？
つまり
呼んでも応じてくれないなら
So if they won't respond to our summons,
we should just make a new one?
新しく誕生させろってことか…
Right!
This won't be easy.
（リムル）
簡単じゃないな
適性も心配だし…
I'm concerned about their affinities...
But I guess there's no other choice.
それでも やるしかない
I have Degenerate, a special skill that
specializes in unification and separation.
俺には統合と分離に特化した
ユニークスキル“変質者”がある
Degenerate
魔王レオンにできて
俺にできないわけがない！
If Demon Lord Leon could do it,
there's no way I can't.
みんな
Everyone...
Y-Yeah.
（リョウタ）大丈夫です
We're ready.
Sensei...
先生…
へ… 平気に決まってるじゃない
O-Of course we're all right!
頑張ります！
We'll do our best!
（ランガ）ワフ！　その意気だ！
That's the spirit!
よし！
Right!
Kenya, Ryota, Gale, Alice, Chloe...
ケンヤ リョウタ ゲイル
アリス クロエ
Let's do this!
やるぞ！
Yeah!
（一同）はい！
Shizu-san, wherever you
are, are you watching?
（リムル）
シズさん どこかで見ているか？
I'll make sure
シズさんの思い
your wish is realized.
俺が果たしてやるから
Next time, "Saved Souls."
（大賢者）
次回「救われる魂」
Saved  Souls